<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Labor Predictor</string>
    <string name="about">*test lines*\nPut something in about section !\n\nrandom text\n\na. Ultra scan
As shown in Figure 3, an ultrasound scan sends sound waves through womb (uterus). These waves bounce off the baby as echoes. The echoes are turned into an image on a screen that shows fetal position and movements. Hard tissues such as bone, reflect the sound waves and make the biggest echoes. It includes white in the image and soft tissues as grey. Fluids such as the amniotic fluid surrounding the baby appear as black. This is because the sound waves go through with no echoes. A first-trimester scan will test that babys heart is beating and also look at the basic examination of babys head, abdominal wall, and limbs.\n\n
b. Doppler Ultrasound
A Doppler is a form of ultrasound scan that helps to assess babys health [4]. It measures the blood flow in different parts of fetal body, such as umbilical cord, brain, and heart. This helps to show whether fetal is getting all the oxygen and nutrients needs via the placenta.The transducer sends out sound waves, which bounces off the blood flow to fetal body through the cord as well as his blood circulation system. This creates an image on a display which shows how the blood is flowing.  This is shown in Figure 3.\n\nc. CT Scan
A doctor or physician may order a Computerized tomography (CT) scan of the fetus to formulate detailed pictures and analyze the internal structure. Computerized Tomography (CT) scanning is useful to get a very detailed 3D image of certain parts of the body. The same is shown in Figure 4
</string>
    <string name="userguide">*test lines*\nPut something in user guide section !\n\nrandom text\n\na. Ultra scan
As shown in Figure 3, an ultrasound scan sends sound waves through womb (uterus). These waves bounce off the baby as echoes. The echoes are turned into an image on a screen that shows fetal position and movements. Hard tissues such as bone, reflect the sound waves and make the biggest echoes. It includes white in the image and soft tissues as grey. Fluids such as the amniotic fluid surrounding the baby appear as black. This is because the sound waves go through with no echoes. A first-trimester scan will test that babys heart is beating and also look at the basic examination of babys head, abdominal wall, and limbs.\n\n
b. Doppler Ultrasound
A Doppler is a form of ultrasound scan that helps to assess babys health [4]. It measures the blood flow in different parts of fetal body, such as umbilical cord, brain, and heart. This helps to show whether fetal is getting all the oxygen and nutrients needs via the placenta.The transducer sends out sound waves, which bounces off the blood flow to fetal body through the cord as well as his blood circulation system. This creates an image on a display which shows how the blood is flowing.  This is shown in Figure 3.\n\nc. CT Scan
A doctor or physician may order a Computerized tomography (CT) scan of the fetus to formulate detailed pictures and analyze the internal structure. Computerized Tomography (CT) scanning is useful to get a very detailed 3D image of certain parts of the body. The same is shown in Figure 4</string>
</resources>
